<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>self-care on web with mizouzie</title>
    <link>https://mizouzie.github.io/web-with-mizouzie/tags/self-care/</link>
    <description>Recent content in self-care on web with mizouzie</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>made by MizouziE</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mizouzie.github.io/web-with-mizouzie/tags/self-care/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>L.I.F.T - the anti-advice that could save you</title>
      <link>https://mizouzie.github.io/web-with-mizouzie/articles/l-i-f-t/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mizouzie.github.io/web-with-mizouzie/articles/l-i-f-t/</guid>
      <description>Leave It For Tomorrow  Seemingly controversial advice to give, but hear me out.
When coding, at least learning to code, you will not only find yourself facing brand new subject matter constantly, but often trying to implement that new thing at the same time. The code you write is always to solve a problem and there are always a multitude of ways to solve it. You&amp;rsquo;ll have to choose which path you take according to other dependencies and the structure you&amp;rsquo;re using.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recognise struggle for what it is</title>
      <link>https://mizouzie.github.io/web-with-mizouzie/articles/recognise-struggle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mizouzie.github.io/web-with-mizouzie/articles/recognise-struggle/</guid>
      <description>In Greek mythology, Sisyphus or Sisyphos (/ˈsɪsɪfəs/; Ancient Greek: Σίσυφος Sísyphos) was the founder and king of Ephyra (now known as Corinth). Zeus punished him for cheating death twice by being forced to roll an immense boulder up a hill only for it to roll down every time it neared the top, repeating this action for eternity. Through the classical influence on modern culture, tasks that are both laborious and futile are therefore described as Sisyphean (/sɪsɪˈfiːən/).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting is one thing, STOPPING is another</title>
      <link>https://mizouzie.github.io/web-with-mizouzie/articles/know-when-to-stop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mizouzie.github.io/web-with-mizouzie/articles/know-when-to-stop/</guid>
      <description>Getting started in web development was one of the best decisions I ever made. It&amp;rsquo;s challenging, fulfilling and has so many avenues of opportunity. I will say, when I first started and began to recognise the scope of it I was a little taken aback. My main thoughts were:
 I&amp;rsquo;ll take forever to reach an employable level All of this is completely foreign to me This stuff is way more complicated under the nice polished UI  My natural instinct to such a seemingly daunting task was to go full throttle for as long as I possibly could to get as far ahead in a short space of time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
